A city of monsters, home to a slime that bested the Orc Lord...
Kota monster, di sanalah tempat tinggal Slime yang mengalahkan Orc Lord ....
Can this be true?
Apa ini nyata?
No, I know it's true.
Tidak, aku tahu ini nyata.
I simply can't believe it.
Ini sulit dipercaya.
But I have to believe it.
Tapi aku harus percaya.
This slime called Rimuru has saved us.
Kita diselamatkan oleh Slime yang bernama Rimuru itu.
True.
Benar.
What sort of relationship should we seek with them?
Sebaiknya hubungan apa yang harus kita jalin dengannya?
And should we do so on the assumption that this slime is benevolent,
Apa kita harus berasumsi bahwa dia makhluk yang penuh dengan kebajikan,
or should we perceive him as a threat and attempt to eliminate him?
atau harus kita anggap sebagai ancaman lalu melenyapkannya?
You speak of eliminating him so easily, but is it even possible?
Mudah sekali kau bilang melenyapkan, lagi pula memangnya itu memungkinkan?
Shall I give you an honest answer?
Mau mendengar jawaban jujurku?
I don't even need to hear it.
Tidak perlu sampai mendengarnya.
I suppose we should go and meet him once.
Sekali saja aku ingin bertemu dengannya.
I will judge this Rimuru with my own two eyes.
Dengan kedua mataku ini aku akan memastikan makhluk macam apa Rimuru itu.
All right, let's move out.
Ayo kita berangkat.
We're going to go see this slime you three met.
Untuk bertemu Slime yang pernah kalian jumpai.
In the night you could count stars in the sky
Menghitung bintang di langit selepas hujan
The overflown drop reflects the swaying world
Tiap tetesnya seakan mampu getarkan dunia
All life are in ambivalence
Setiap peristiwa selalu memiliki alasan
And it twinkles as the days goes by
Melambai dalam keseharian yang terus berjalan
Both short-lived flowers and devastating winds
Bunga-bunga yang berguguran
are the sign of the passing present
Itu bukti hari-hari yang terus berlalu
To those who live in the moment, this song shall reach you
Sebuah lagu yang akan menjangkau
It will push you to the limits of freedom, telling you to survive
Kejar akhir dari kebebasan
We will find the way
Kita akan mencari jalannya
We returners all equally carry a seed of hope
Setiap orang itu sama
Under the whim of miracle, Birth and Demise shall join hand
Awal dan akhir dari keajaiban
This is delicious!
Lezat!
I love all the food in this town!
Aku suka semua makanan yang ada di kota ini!
Give me more!
Tambah lagi!
Were you okay yesterday?
Kamu sudah tidak apa-apa?
Nothing to worry about! I—
Tidak perlu khawatir! Aku—
...am quite tough, you know!
ini lumayan tangguh!
That's Sir Gabiru for you! So cool!
Tuan Gabiru memang hebat! Keren!
Did your communication crystal work okay?
Apa kristal komunikasinya berjalan lancar?
Yes. I was able to contact King Gazel.
Ya. Saya berhasil menghubungi Raja Gazel.
I informed him that the Demon Lord Milim attacked and you dealt with her.
Saya memberitahukan tentang serangan Raja Iblis Milim dan Tuan Rimuru yang sudah mengurusnya.
Good!
Bagus!
We'll just see how things go with Milim for now.
Untuk sekarang kesampingkan dulu urusan tentang Milim.
Be sure to give me a report.
Aku tunggu laporanmu selanjutnya.
Of course.
Tentu.
This is Great Rimuru's healing potion.
Ini adalah ramuan penyembuh Tuan Rimuru.
99% of its composition is extracted from hipokute herbs.
99% komposisinya diekstrak dari Herba Hipokute.
You can drink it or apply it on a wound!
Bisa diminum atau dioles ke luka!
The potion of total recovery: full potion!
Ramuan penyembuh istimewa: ramuan penuh!
In contrast, Dwarven techniques can only extract up to 98%.
Sebaliknya, teknik Dwarf hanya bisa mengekstrak sampai 98%.
The potions we can make are "high potions."
Ramuan yang memungkinkan dibuat adalah "ramuan tingkat tinggi".
A mere 1% makes a tremendous difference in potency.
Satu persen saja bisa membuat perbedaan yang sangat besar.
And now, at last, I've overcome that 1% barrier!
Pada akhirnya, kita bisa melewati dinding 1% itu!
This is the result of my research!
Ini adalah hasil penelitianku!
Oh? All right, I'll appraise it.
Oh? Kalau begitu, aku mau menilainya dulu.
Please do.
Silakan.
Great Sage, use Appraisal.
Petapa Agung, gunakan skill penilaian.
Answer.
Jawaban.
This potion is equal to a full potion.
Ramuan ini setara dengan ramuan penuh.
Well done, Vesta! It's definitely a full potion!
Kerja bagus, Vesta! Tidak salah lagi ini adalah ramuan penuh!
Excellent work, Vesta!
Luar biasa, Vesta!
Assisting you in this endeavor was truly worthwhile!
Jerih payahku ada hasilnya juga!
Way to go, Vesta!
Hebat sekali, Vesta!
I knew you were the right man for this kind of research!
Sudah kuduga hanya kamu yang bisa melakukan penelitian ini!
Thank you... Thank you.
Terima kasih, terima kasih.
Wow, I really didn't think he'd be able to make it.
Yah, ternyata mereka berhasil membuatnya.
Now, if we move forward with mass production...
Kalau kita produksi secara massal ....
I think if we sold this,
Kalau ramuan ini dijual,
it'd be a great source of funds for Tempest. What do you say?
ini akan menjadi pemasukan besar bagi Tempest. Bagaimana?
I don't think that's gonna be easy.
Sepertinya bakal sulit.
This potion is too effective.
Ramuan ini terlalu bagus.
We can't rely on it for everyday use.
Kita tidak boleh menggunakannya untuk luka kecil.
Fine quality like this
Ramuan sebagus ini ...
is best reserved for high-level champions in life-or-death situations.
... lebih baik digunakan pada situasi yang genting.
That's true.
Benar sekali.
The potions sold in the Dwarven Kingdom are low potions,
Ramuan yang dijual di Kerajaan Dwarf adalah ramuan tingkat rendah ...
which are mass-produced by diluting high potions.
... yang berasal dari larutan ramuan tingkat tinggi.
What do you say to negotiating with King Gazel
Bagaimana kalau kita negosiasi dengan Raja Gazel ...
to have those low potions produced here in Tempest?
... untuk memproduksi ramuan tingkat rendah itu di Tempest?
Hey, that could work!
Itu ide bagus!
If we produce and sell the potions here,
Kalau kita memproduksi dan menjual ramuan di sini,
the Dwarven Kingdom would only need to procure the necessary ingredients.
Kerajaan Dwarf hanya perlu membeli bahan-bahan yang diperlukan.
I get it. That would benefit both nations, huh?
Begitu, ya. Itu akan menguntungkan kedua belah pihak, ya?
Okay. Let's bring that up for negotiation.
Sip. Ayo kita negosiasikan.
You guys can continue with the production here.
Kalian bisa melanjutkan produksinya di sini.
Yes, sir!
Baik!
What's going on?
Apa yang terjadi?
A new guest arrived in town,
Ada tamu yang berkunjung ke sini,
and Lady Milim took exception to him.
lalu Nona Milim menghajarnya.
Let me through.
Biarkan aku lewat.
Rigurd, are you okay?
Rigurd, kamu tidak apa-apa?
G-Great Rimuru, it's you!
Tu-Tuan Rimuru!
Huh?!
Eh?
This is no cause for concern at all!
Luka seperti ini sama sekali bukan masalah!
No way! That's serious!
Mana ada! Parah banget, tahu!
This is who did that to you?
Dia yang melakukannya?
Correct.
Betul.
Oh, Rimuru!
Oh, Rimuru!
Yikes.
Duh.
This guy thought he could mock us, so I taught him a lesson!
Karena dia meremehkan kita, jadi aku memberinya pelajaran!
I am one of Demon Lord Carrion's Three Beastketeers,
Aku adalah salah satu dari Tiga Musketir Raja Iblis Carrion.
Phobio the Black Leopard Fang.
Taring Macan Tutul Hitam, Phobio.
I am the strongest warrior of the Beast King's Beastketeers.
Prajurit terkuat di antara prajurit monster Raja Monster.
Nice town you've got here.
Kota ini lumayan juga.
Fit to be ruled by the Beast King, don't you think?
Cocok untuk dikuasai oleh Raja Monster. Kamu juga berpikiran sama, 'kan?
Surely you jest—
Jangan bercan—
The Demon Lord Milim?!
Raja Iblis Milim?
Leopard Fang Flaming Palm!
Pukulan Api Taring Macan Tutul!
What do you think you're doing to my bestie's subordinate?!
Apa yang kamu lakukan pada anak buah sahabatku?
I think she expects me to praise her.
Kayaknya dia pengin dipuji.
And, um...
Ini mah ....
Should I really be praising her for this?
Dalam situasi begini, apa aku boleh memujinya?
I doubt she'll get away with doing this to an underling of this Demon Lord Carrion.
Pastinya ini akan memicu konflik karena kami sudah menghajar anak buah dari Raja Iblis Carrion.
Didn't you promise not to cause any commotion without my permission?
Bukannya kamu sudah berjanji untuk tidak mengamuk tanpa izin dariku?
Huh?!
Eh?
Er, well...
Eng, itu ....
Y-Yeah! This is different!
I-Ini kan berbeda!
He's not from this town, so it doesn't count!
Dia bukan berasal dari sini, jadi tidak dihitung!
It does count.
Dihitung, tahu!
Huh?!
Eh?
But since you did stand up for Rigurd,
Tapi, karena kamu sudah melindungi Rigurd,
I'll just make you go without lunch today.
hukumanmu cuma puasa makan siang.
That's cruel... That's too cruel!
Jahat! Jahat banget!
This is all his fault!
Semua ini salah dia!
This scumbag!
Dasar kurang ajar!
One hit wasn't enough! At least give me one more—
Satu pukulan saja tidak cukup! Setidaknya satu pukulan la—
Wait! Wait! Wait!
Tunggu! Tunggu! Tunggu!
So, why did you come here?
Jadi, ada urusan apa di sini?
Hmph. You expect me to answer a lowly slime?
Hmph. Kamu pikir aku akan menjawab pertanyaan dari Slime rendahan?
You may call me "lowly," but I'm stronger than you.
Kamu memanggilku "rendahan", tapi aku ini lebih kuat darimu, lo.
I don't know this Demon Lord Carrion.
Lagian aku tidak kenal sama Raja Iblis Carrion.
Depending on how you behave, my people could become Carrion's enemies.
Tergantung dari sikapmu, bisa jadi Carrion kami anggap musuh.
Do you want to be solely responsible for antagonizing the entire Great Forest of Jura?
Memangnya kamu mau bertanggung jawab kalau seisi Hutan Agung Jura ini menjadi musuhmu?
Hah! That's big talk.
Hah! Sombong sekali.
This whole town is loyal to a lowly monster like you?
Penduduk di sini tunduk sama monster rendahan sepertimu?
Must be rough having nothing but weaklings around.
Dikelilingi oleh keroco semua pasti repot, ya.
Don't get a big head just because Lady Milim took a liking to you.
Jangan berlagak sombong hanya karena Nona Milim menyukaimu.
Hey! Are you talking trash about my friend?
Hei, kamu! Jangan berkata buruk kepada temanku.
Milim, stop. If you do anything else, you can kiss dinner goodbye.
Milim, diam dulu. Kalau cari masalah lagi, tidak akan aku beri makan malam.
Okay. I'll be quiet.
Oke. Aku akan diam.
Now, it's true that I'm a slime.
Begini, aku ini memang Slime.
But it's also a fact that I rule 30% of this forest,
Tapi nyatanya aku menguasai sekitar 30% hutan ini,
and if you're really serious, we may have no choice but to declare war.
dan kalau kalian bersikeras, aku tidak akan ragu untuk menyatakan perang.
So think carefully before you answer me.
Sebaiknya jaga sikapmu dan jawab pertanyaanku baik-baik.
Lord Carrion ordered me to come here and scout some mysterious majin to serve him.
Aku diperintah Raja Carrion datang ke sini untuk merekrut beberapa Majin misterius.
Oh? He must mean us.
Oh? Mungkin maksudnya kita.
Looks like Milim wasn't the only Demon Lord who had an eye on that battle.
Bukan cuma Milim, sepertinya Raja Iblis lain juga menyaksikan pertarungan itu.
Damn that Carrion! He broke his promise!
Dasar Carrion! Dia melanggar janjinya!
Well, I get the picture.
Aku sudah mengerti.
You can leave now.
Kalian boleh pergi.
Huh?
Eh?
Great Rimuru...
Tuan Rimuru ....
Are you sure about this?
Apa Anda yakin?
Well, I can't kill him, can I?
Lagi pula, kita tidak boleh membunuhnya.
Tell the Demon Lord Carrion
Sampaikan ke Raja Iblis Carrion ...
that if he wants to talk, he can choose a date and contact us again.
... kalau mau berbicara dengan kami, dia bisa menentukan tempat dan waktunya.
I'll make you regret this.
Kupastikan kalian akan menyesal.
Doesn't look like he'll relay any message for us...
Kayaknya dia tidak akan menyampaikan pesanku.
Okay, I want to know all about this Demon Lord Carrion.
Nah, aku mau tanya tentang Raja Iblis Carrion.
I can't tell you that.
Aku tidak bisa menjawabnya.
We've sworn not to interfere with each other.
Karena kami sudah berjanji untuk tidak mengganggu satu sama lain.
And there it is! She just confessed that there's some secret!
Nah! Dia baru saja mengaku kalau mereka punya rahasia!
Did you only make that promise with Carrion?
Apa itu cuma perjanjian dengan Carrion saja?
Or does it involve other Demon Lords, too?
Atau Raja Iblis lain juga ikut terlibat?
Uh, that's...
Eng, soal itu ....
Hey, it's okay!
Tidak masalah, kok!
Carrion used his underling to interfere with you, didn't he?
Carrion juga datang mengganggu dengan mengirim anak buahnya, 'kan?
And we're besties, so we help each other out, right?
Kita kan sahabat, harus tolong menolong, dong?
So I think it'd be a good idea for me to know about the other Demon Lords.
Jadi sebaiknya aku juga harus tahu tentang Raja Iblis selain kamu.
If I don't know what kind of promise you made,
Kalau aku tidak tahu janji apa yang kalian sepakati,
I might end up interfering without realizing it.
bisa saja tanpa sadar aku mengganggu rencana kalian.
That's true...
Benar juga ....
But... Besties...
Tapi ... sahabat ....
I know!
Oh, iya!
I'll make a weapon for you!
Aku akan membuatkanmu senjata nanti!
I'm concerned for you as your bestie, after all!
Sebagai sahabat, aku sangat peduli padamu, Milim!
A new weapon?!
Senjata baru?
Yeah, that's right!
Benar juga, ya!
Nothing's more important than your bestie!
Sahabat itu memang nomor satu!
Too easy. She's way too easy.
Gampang. Dia terlalu gampangan.
Demon Lords Clayman, Carrion, Frey,
Raja Iblis Clayman, Carrion, Frey,
and you, Milim, used Gelmud in a scheme to create a puppet Demon Lord.
dan kamu, Milim, menggunakan Gelmud sebagai boneka Raja Iblis.
It was just a way to kill time.
Itu cuma iseng saja, kok.
Maybe that's all it was to you,
Bagimu memang cuma iseng,
but since we butted in, I guess it's inevitable that they'd target us.
tapi semenjak kami ikut campur, sudah sewajarnya mereka mengincar kami, ya.
It seems likely that other Demon Lords will become involved, as well.
Sepertinya Raja Iblis lain juga akan ikut campur.
What a predicament...
Sungguh cobaan ....
We must consult with Lady Treyni.
Kita harus diskusikan dengan Nona Treyni.
It'll be fine!
Tenang saja!
Great Rimuru has nothing to fear from any of those Demon Lords!
Bagi Tuan Rimuru, tidak ada yang harus ditakutkan dari Raja Iblis.
Well, I've told you the secret.
Dengan begitu, aku sudah memberi tahu rahasianya.
Now give me my new weapon, like you promised, bestie!
Sesuai janji, buatkan aku senjata baru, ya, sahabatku!
The storm that arose along with Demon Lord Milim's attack
Badai yang turut berdatangan bersama dengan serangan Raja Iblis Milim ...
would gain strength along its path
... akan semakin kuat seiring waktu ...
to swallowing up Rimuru's nation and his people.
... untuk melahap Rimuru dan rakyatnya.
One of the nations surrounding the Great Forest of Jura, the Kingdom of Falmuth,
Salah satu negara di sekitar Hutan Agung Jura, Kerajaan Falmuth,
is a major trade power known as the gateway to the Western Provinces.
dikenal sebagai pusat perdagangan dari Wilayah Barat.
It was from this kingdom
Itulah tim yang dikirim oleh ...
that a team was sent to the Forest of Jura to learn about the Orc Lord.
... kerajaan untuk menyelidiki Orc Lord di Hutan Agung Jura.
Led by a man named Youm,
Dipimpin oleh lelaki bernama Youm,
they're a rowdy gang, brought together by money.
mereka adalah perkumpulan yang disatukan oleh uang.
-Boss— -Shh.
Ketua—
Whoa, this is bad!
Duh, gawat!
But, but...
Tapi, tapi ....
You guys... Whoa! Watch it!
Hei, kalian ... hati-hati, dong!
How have you three stayed alive so long by being this careless?!
Bagaimana bisa kalian bertahan hidup padahal selalu gegabah begini?
Sounds like some people have encountered a monster.
Kelihatannya ada kelompok yang sedang berhadapan dengan monster.
What should we do, boss?
Ketua, kita harus bagaimana?
Hey! Wait for us!
Hei! Tunggu, dong!
Sorry to butt in!
Permisi!
We appreciate the help!
Terima kasih bantuannya!
Sorry about this!
Maaf, ya!
Here it comes!
Dia datang!
A Knight Spider?!
Knight Spider?!
All right, boys, assume formation.
Kalian semua, siapkan formasi.
Remove and heal anyone who gets hurt.
Kalau ada yang terluka, segera sembuhkan.
This is an order! Everyone stay alive!
Ini perintah! Jangan ada yang mati!
Yeah!
Ya!
Kajir, take command.
Kajir, ambil komando.
Got it.
Dimengerti.
Rommel, use a strengthening spell on me.
Rommel, rapalkan sihir penguatan kepadaku.
And you guys...
Dan kalian ....
I'll make you pay for getting us involved in this later.
Nanti aku akan membuatmu membayar karena sudah melibatkan kami.
Hey, Kaval! Is that you?
Wah, bukannya kamu Kaval?
Good to see you again!
Lama tidak bertemu!
Gobta!
Gobta!
You're fighting monsters every time I see you.
Sebelumnya kamu juga sedang bertarung dengan monster.
Do you enjoy fighting that much?
Kamu sebegitu sukanya bertarung, ya?
But I'll handle this one.
Tapi kali ini biar aku saja.
You're for dinner today!
Kau akan kujadikan makan malam!
You're kidding me...
Serius, nih?
These things are seriously delicious, you know!
Dia ini lezat banget, lo!
It'll be ready soon!
Sebentar lagi matang!
I can't wait!
Aku sudah tidak sabar!
I'm the representative of this town... or nation...
Aku perwakilan dari kota ... atau negara ....
called the Jura Tempest Federation. My name's Rimuru Tempest.
Federasi Jura Tempest. Namaku Rimuru Tempest.
You really are a slime!
Ternyata Slime sungguhan!
By the way, Rimuru, there are some folks here we didn't see last time.
Omong-omong, Tuan Rimuru, sepertinya ada orang yang belum pernah kulihat.
Oh, yeah. This is Benimaru, Shion, Souei, and Shuna.
Oh. Dia Benimaru, Shion, Souei, dan Shuna.
And that's Milim.
Ditambah Milim.
So, the Kingdoms of Blumund and Falmuth have both come to investigate this place?
Jadi, Kerajaan Blumund dan Falmuth sama- sama datang untuk menyelidiki tempat ini?
-We are— -Wait a minute.
Kami—
Why is a slime acting like such a bigshot?
Kenapa Slime ini bertingkah sok berkuasa banget?
It makes no sense!
Aneh, tahu!
What's the deal here?
Kok bisa begitu?
Why are all of you okay with this?
Kenapa kalian tidak ada yang protes?
You are insulting Great Rimuru.
Kamu menghina Tuan Rimuru.
Shut your mouth, Tits!
Diam saja kamu, tetek!
-Boss! -Youm!
Youm! Bos!
H-Hey...
He-Hei ....
I'm sorry!
Maaf!
Sorry about what Shion did.
Tolong maafkan Shion, ya.
She has trouble restraining herself sometimes.
Terkadang dia tidak bisa menahan diri.
Cut her some slack.
Maklumi saja.
That's mean! I'm actually known for my patience!
Jahat! Sebenarnya saya juga sudah cukup menahan diri!
You've got a long way to go if you're that impatient, Shion!
Itu masih jauh dari menahan diri, lo, Shion!
You're so short-tempered because you don't have an open mind like I do.
Itu karena kamu tidak berpikiran terbuka, makanya jadi pemarah sepertiku.
I want to be on good terms with Humans.
Aku bermaksud untuk hidup berdampingan dengan manusia.
I hope we can trade and network with you all someday, too.
Aku juga berharap nantinya kami bisa berdagang dan membangun koneksi dengan kalian semua.
Trade?
Berdagang?
Yeah.
Ya.
We've actually entered diplomatic relations with the Dwarven Kingdom already.
Sebenarnya kami sudah punya hubungan diplomatik dengan Kerajaan Dwarf.
With Dwargon?!
Dengan Dwargon?
I think passing through this land would be more convenient for your merchants.
Kurasa dengan melintasi wilayah ini, akan memudahkan kalian untuk berdagang.
What do you think?
Bagaimana?
Now, wait a minute!
Tunggu sebentar!
You're saying that Dwargon acknowledges this nation of monsters as legitimate?
Kamu bilang Dwargon mau berdagang dengan negara monster?
I can vouch for that.
Aku bisa menjamin pembicaraan tadi.
Minister Vesta!
Menteri Vesta!
Former minister.
Mantan menteri.
What is a man of your standing doing here?
Orang penting seperti Anda kenapa bisa berada di sini?
It's good to see you again, Fuze.
Lama tidak bertemu, Fuze.
What Great Rimuru says is true.
Yang dikatakan Tuan Rimuru benar nyatanya.
King Gazel and Rimuru have entered into a treaty.
Raja Gazel dan Rimuru sudah membuat perjanjian.
Are you convinced now?
Apa kalian sudah percaya?
W-Well... If that is the case, we aren't opposed to cooperating with you.
Ya-Yah ... kalau begitu, kami tidak akan menolak untuk bekerja sama denganmu.
But I'll need to see undeniable proof that you are, in fact, an ally of Humans.
Tapi aku harus membuktikan apakah kamu benar-benar berada di pihak manusia.
I assume that's all right?
Tidak masalah, 'kan?
Oh, sure. That's to be expected.
Oh, tentu. Itu sudah sewajarnya.
I'm just fine with that.
Aku tidak keberatan.
I'll permit you to stay here.
Sementara kamu boleh tinggal di sini.
I want you to understand that we aren't a threat.
Demi memastikan kalau kami tidaklah berbahaya.
By the way, Fuze-san,
Oh, iya, Fuze,
has the news that the Orc Lord was defeated already gotten around?
sudah dengar informasi tentang Orc Lord yang baru dikalahkan?
No, only our king and a select handful of people know that.
Soal itu, hanya raja dan orang kepercayaannya yang tahu.
I see. In that case...
Oh. Kalau begitu ....
Youm-kun, want to make a contract with me?
Youm, mau membuat kontrak denganku?
Huh? What are you even talki—
Hah? Omong apa, sih—
What... might you be suggesting?
Tadi ... apa yang Anda tanyakan?
You said the Kingdom of Falmuth hired you with money, right?
Sebelumnya kamu bilang kalau kalian disewa oleh Kerajaan Falmuth, 'kan?
So you'd just be switching employers.
Jadi, kamu hanya perlu mengganti penyewa saja.
To put it in simple terms...
Singkatnya ....
I want you guys to be the champions who defeated the Orc Lord.
Aku ingin kalian menjadi pahlawan yang mengalahkan Orc Lord.
What?!
Hah?
Just say that we simply helped you out,
Dengan bekerja sama dengan kalian,
and start a rumor that you were the one who defeated the Orc Lord.
kita akan menyebarkan rumor tentang kalianlah yang mengalahkan Orc Lord.
I figure, that way,
Dengan begitu,
I can be known as the trustworthy monster who assisted the champion.
Aku akan dikenal sebagai monster baik yang sudah membantu pahlawan.
I think it'll be easier to befriend people that way
Kurasa itu adalah cara terbaik untuk mengakali ...
than if they think I'm some mysterious, threatening monster.
... kalau aku bukanlah monster yang berbahaya.
What do you say?
Bagaimana?
I get it.
Benar juga.
Well put.
Ide bagus.
Have you gathered your thoughts?
Sudah dipikirkan baik-baik?
Rimuru... No, Mr. Rimuru.
Rimuru ....
This town is really something.
Kota ini benar-benar sesuatu.
After seeing all of them, I know you're not some evil being.
Hanya dengan melihat mereka, aku bisa tahu kalau kamu bukan monster yang jahat.
We are people of guilty conscience.
Kami, manusia itu sudah berlumuran dosa.
We always longed to be free men.
Kami selalu mengharapkan kebebasan.
We accepted the mission to come here
Kami menerima misi kali ini ...
because we planned to make everyone think we'd died on the way
... karena ingin pura-pura gugur dalam misi ...
and then head for some safe nation.
... lalu pergi ke sebuah negara yang aman.
I've decided.
Sudah kuputuskan.
I'll trust you.
Aku memercayaimu.
Allow me to call you "Master Rimuru" from now on.
Mulai sekarang aku akan memanggilmu "Tuan Rimuru".
I am at your command.
Mohon bantuannya.
Sure. I'll be counting on you.
Tentu. Aku mengandalkanmu.
Thus, Youm and his companions began training under Hakurou
Dengan begitu, Youm dan kawan- kawan mulai berlatih ...
to look like champions.
... di bawah bimbingan Hakurou agar bisa terlihat seperti pahlawan sungguhan.
That didn't take long.
Lumayan cepat juga, ya.
You weren't noticed, were you, Tear?
Apa kamu tidak menyadarinya, Tear?
I'm part of the Moderate Harlequin Alliance, too, you know!
Aku ini salah satu anggota Aliansi Badut Veteran, juga, tahu!
Have a little faith in me!
Jangan meragukanku, dong!
I'm just concerned you might go overboard.
Aku hanya cemas takutnya kamu bertindak gegabah.
Jeez! Stop treating me like a child already!
Duh! Jangan perlakukan aku seperti anak kecil terus, dong!
Very well.
Baiklah.
I received word from Myulan.
Aku mendapat laporan dari Myulan.
It seems Milim has taken quite a liking to those majin.
Sepertinya Milim sangat menyukai para monster itu.
Huh...
Eh ....
This is turning out to be more interesting than I expected.
Kelihatannya ini akan menjadi semakin menarik.
How truly delightful.
Benar-benar bikin penasaran.
Well, that's great,
Bagus kalau begitu,
but what's really going on?
tapi apa yang sebenarnya terjadi?
Is this majin really so amazing that the Demon Lord Milim would take interest?
Memangnya Majin itu sangat hebat sampai- sampai bisa disukai Raja Iblis Milim?
Only to the point that we mustn't simply ignore it.
Hanya sebatas tidak boleh kita abaikan saja.
He was no match for me, after all.
Lagi pula dia bukan tandinganku.
But then again, Laplace...
Tapi, Laplace ....
What about Laplace?
Laplace?
Shall we call it... an eeriness?
Mungkin bisa disebut ... keseraman?
He says he felt something of that nature.
Katanya dia merasakan sesuatu.
Oh, really?
Oh, masa?
If a cunning guy like Laplace said so, maybe there really is something!
Kalau si licik Laplace bilang begitu, mungkin memang benaran ada sesuatu!
At the very least,
Setidaknya,
I think we should find out why the Demon Lord Milim's taken such an interest.
Kita harus tahu alasan Raja Iblis Milim bisa menyukai mereka.
Yes, we certainly will need to gather more information and give it some thought.
Benar, lebih baik kita kumpulkan banyak informasi lalu ambil kesimpulannya.
Yeah, we should!
Iya, harus begitu!
So, as for the results of my investigation!
Jadi, ini hasil penyelidikanku!
Let's hear it.
Mari kudengar.
Well, Frey apparently has no interest in getting involved with the Forest of Jura.
Sepertinya Frey sama sekali tidak ingin terlibat dengan Hutan Jura.
She seemed wary of something.
Seperti sedang waspada terhadap sesuatu.
It was almost as if she was preparing for battle!
Bagaikan dia sedang bersiap untuk berperang!
And did you find out the reason for that?
Apa kamu tahu penyebabnya?
I did! You won't believe this!
Tahu! Ini cukup mengagetkan, lo!
She was freaking out, saying Charybdis was going to be revived!
Dia ketakutan karena Charybdis bakal dibangkitkan!
Charybdis?
Charybdis?
I see.
Begitu.
Now, Tear, I have another task I'd like you to handle.
Kalau begitu, Tear, aku akan memberimu tugas lagi.
I thought you would!
Aku sudah menduganya!
I've already called Footman, so a little fighting is no problem!
Aku sudah merekrut Footman juga, jadi kalau ada pertarungan kecil tidak akan masalah!
That's wonderful, Tear.
Inisiatif sekali, Tear.
But I would like you to avoid violence as much as possible.
Tapi, sebisa mungkin hindari pertarungan, ya.
First, seek out the location of the seal
Pertama, cari wilayah yang tersegel itu ...
and find out whether or not we can tame Charybdis.
... lalu, cari cara apakah kita bisa mengendalikan Charybdis.
Leave it to me, Clayman!
Serahkan padaku, Clayman!
-The location should be— -I said leave it to me!
Tempatnya mungkin—
Okay, I'm going now!
Kalau begitu, aku berangkat dulu!
Charybdis, eh?
Charybdis, ya?
With power said to rival that of the Demon Lords...
Dengan kekuatan yang setara dengan Raja Iblis ....
I truly look forward to seeing what it is like.
Aku sungguh menantikan ia akan seperti apa.
I have to believe in me that you believe in
Kau percaya padaku
A story just started, carrying a name
Bawa nama kisah yang baru dimulai ini!
Whether it's a concidence or a fate, who cares?
Entah kebetulan ataupun takdir
Just pick one thing in here
Sekarang semua yang ada di sini
Just from one chance, the future would change
Meski hanya ada satu kesempatan
Along with the sky, the wind, and the land
Bahkan langit, angin, maupun bumi mulai bersatu
It's all because you keep believing in that possiblity
Ini semua menjadi mungkin
That I can also keep believing. With my power...
Jadi akan kujaga kekuatan
In the depths of the world that we must protect,
Berdiri di ujung dunia yang harus kulindungi
rise up as many times as it take
Tidak peduli berapa kali harus bangkit
If I can't hold it with both hands, I'll lend it to you
Bila mampu genggam dengan kedua tangan
Even if you got shaken, face foward for the smile you wish to protect
Selama demi lindungi senyuman itu
There's a scenary I want to show you,
Karena ada pemandangan yang ingin kulihat bersamamu
let's go togehter
Jadi mari ke sana bersama!
Next time, "Evil Creeps Closer."
Selanjutnya, "Rambatan Kedengkian".